Guide to the Miscellaneous documents, 1326-1867
Department of Special Collections
Miscellaneous documents,
1326-1867
Special Collections M0535
36 items (1 linear ft.)
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1989.
Scope and Content
Apparently unrelated documents, primarily 17th & 18th century, in French and German, but also a few in Old French, English, Italian, Latin, and Arabic. Many from Bern (some of these are related) and one each from Geneva, Paris, Kensington, & London. Includes apprenticeship papers, monetary accounts, contracts, a marriage announcement, a medical or coroner's report, and a life annuity contract.
Access Terms
Social history--17th century.; Social history--18th century.; Bern (Switzerland)--Social conditions.; Medieval and Renaissance studies--France--14th century.; Paleography.; 14th century--France.; 17th century--France.; 18th century--France.; 17th century--Germany.; 18th century--Germany.; 18th century--Italy.; 17th century--Switzerland.; 18th century--Switzerland.
Container List
- Arabic, n.d.Three documents. Seems to be a line of Hebrew at end of first document. (Box 1, Folder 1)
- English, 1748/1776.London. Receipt for order of teas from Frederick Bull. Signed by Bull and J. Wilson March 15, 1748.Taped to receipt: affidavit of prior work as servant by Mary Edwards. Signed by Frederick Bull, M. Plomer and Mary Edwards. Sept. 6, 1776. (Box OS Box)
- English, March 9, 1826.re: Land given to Kensington Canal Company, Parish of Kensington, Parish of Fulham. George Whitehead named. (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Old French, [1326 and 1387?,on last page]. Signature reads Lomront. (Box OS Box)
- French, Aug. [1600?]. Du nom de Dieu amen... (Box 1, Folder 3)
- French, Sept. 25, 1638.France. Document re: Hon. Jacques Pihoes et Sarra. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- French, 1657.Contract. (Box 1, Folder 5)
- French, Aug, 25, 1666.Twelve documents re: Lanaz de Shilibert, Recognoissance... (Box 1, Folder 6)
- French, April 1, 1681.Geneva, Switzerland. Contract d'acquis pour le Ss. Jacques Mallet Genou Marchand. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- French, April 9, 1696.France. Some sort of contract re: Parrish of Chastillion, Parrish of St. Sigismond, Claude Brubet and Henry Borbut. (Box 1, Folder 8)
- French, 1700.Account book. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- French, after 1765.Réponse... (Box 1, Folder 10)
- French, Nov. 1779(copy dated Aug, 8, 1794).Bern, Switzerland. Rentes Viageres a Dix pourcent... Edict re: Life-annuity contracts. Various beneficiaries are listed. 4 documents in 4 separate folders in oversize. (Box OS Box)
- French, Apr. 7, 1815.Paris, France. Bill of Sale from Duban, merchantin porcelain, crystal, etc. Sales to M. Derougemou. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- French, 1845.Notissen...Villars. List of accounts. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- French, Jan. 7, 1867.Marriage announcement of Justin Richard et Brisset and Virginie Flugenin on Jan. 25, 1867. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Old French, n.d.Document in vellum inidentified. (Box OS Box)
- French, n.d.[Berne?] Lettre d'Acquis pour trois pieces de Vignes...Pierre Sonnier de Vuillars. (Box 1, Folder 14)
- French, n.d.Notes on the Riviere Arve from Cluse to Bonneville. Re: canal reconstruction. (Box 1, Folder 15)
- German, Mar. 12, 1681.Notary signature J.A. Tribollet. (Box 1, Folder 16)
- German, 1715.Germany. Lahen...Brieff. [Apprenticeship papers?] (Box 1, Folder 17)
- German, May 30, 1729.Bern. Lahen...Brieff. (Box 1, Folder 18)
- German, 1747.Lültbrieff, no. 19. [Contract?] (Box 1, Folder 19)
- German/Latin, May 6, 1764.Medical report or Coroner's report for Peter Midey[?] (Box 1, Folder 20)
- German, 1788.Copia...Zundmorfung. (Box 1, Folder 21)
- German, 1792.Document re: Daniel Aubord. (Box 1, Folder 22)
- German, [1823, 1825?].Bern. Brief re David Glohuer. (Box 1, Folder 23)
- German, Oct. 1832.Unidentified. (Box 1, Folder 24)
- German, [1831, 1835?].Bern. Sartner attord mit Courincour. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- German, n.d.[Bill of sale or contract?] (Box 1, Folder 26)
- German/Latin, n.d.[Prayer, page from diary or journal?] Name mentioned is M. Rüfett. (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Italian, Nov. 1, 1799.Household accounts and materials required for baking. German word list translated for Italian. (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Latin (French Romance), Aug. 22, 1418.France. Extrait de convention au regard de la riviere de Bonnet (copied, n.d.).Town of Bonavilla mentioned. (Box OS Box)